# **TIMOTHY HOWARD**

37 Winstone Ave, Chartwell, Hamilton, New Zealand timhow38@gmail.com
022 587 8266

https://www.linkedin.com/in/timhow20 | https://coreos.io

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Experienced Service Desk Agent with a demonstrated history of working in the higher education industry. Skilled in Sales, Service Desk, Software Installation, PowerShell, and Printer Support. Strong support professional with a (Level 7) Bachelor of Applied Information Technology.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# Waikato Institute of Technology

Hamilton, New Zealand Apr 2018 - Apr 2018

# Waikato Institute of Technology

Hamilton, New Zealand Jan 2017 - Present

#### **Bed Post**

Hamilton, New Zealand Jan 2016 - Dec 2016

#### **Events Assistant**

Assisting or presenting events on behalf of multiple Wintec departments.

#### **Service Desk Agent**

- -Providing technical support to Wintec's internal customers.
- -Provided customer support to staff and students via phone, email and face-to-face on the service desk.

#### (approx 840 staff and 20,000 students).

- -Assisted in the training of new staff on the service desk.
- -Logging jobs, elevating tickets and resolving level 1 and 2 issues using Zendesk.
- -Supporting staff experiencing issues with Windows, Office software, Outlook, Projectors, Mobile Phones, Company and BYO computers.

#### **Delivery & Sales Person**

Sales & Delivery - In-store sales and product knowledge. - Office work including invoicing and general phone support.

Product delivery & setup on site / in-store.

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

# Waikato Institute of Technology

Hamilton, New Zealand 2018 - Present

## **Bachelor of Applied Information Technology**

Major: "Web Development"

**Included Papers:** 

**Year 01:** Information Technology Operations - Fundamentals of Programming and Problem Solving - Professional Practice - Business Systems Analysis and Design - Introduction to Networks - Operating Systems and Systems Support - Database Principles, Technical Support - Object Oriented Programming - Database Modelling and SQL - Mathematics for Information Technology

**Year 02:** Interpersonal Communications - Data Visualization - Web Development - Cyber Security - Web Programming - The Web Environment

**Year 03:** Human Computer Interaction - Mobile Applications
Development - Web Applications Development - Business
Essentials for IT Professionals / Project Management Industry

## Placement/Internship:

Design Factory -Wintec

The Gig - Peer Tutoring Prototyping

# Waikato Institute of Technology

Hamilton, New Zealand 2017 - 2018

# Waikato Institute of Technology

Hamilton, New Zealand 2016 - 2017

# Waikato Institute of Technology

Hamilton, New Zealand 2015 - 2016

## Saint Johns College

New Zealand Diploma in Information Technology & Technical Support (Level 5)

# New Zealand Certificate in Information Technology (Level 5)

National Certificate in Computing (Level 3)

NCEA (Level 2)

Hamilton, New Zealand 2015

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Restricted Car License with IR endorsements
- CE -Call Centre Support / Remote Support
- Problem analysis and troubleshooting.
- Active Directory -PowerShell Interaction
- ReactJS, WebPack, Angular,
   PHP, HTML5- Web Frameworks
- Event Planning, Management

- Zendesk Support -Logging,
   Handling and Solving Cases.
- General Software Support Including: Adobe, Office365, Win & Mac and more.
- Employee Training
- VMware Virtualization
- CSS, SASS, JSS Style Scripting

## **INTERESTS**

- Road Cycling
- Local Quiz Nights

• Web Applications & UI Design

### **REFEREES**

## Sanjay Weerasinghe

Manager Technology Services - Waikato Institute of Technology - ITS sanjay.weerasinghe@wintec.ac.nz 274969612

#### **Stewart Hardie**

Systems Engineer - Waikato Institute of Technology stewart.hardie@wintec.ac.nz 0278277290